export const wordPairs = [
  { front: "de", back: "the" },
  { front: "zijn", back: "to be" },
  { front: "en", back: "and" },
  { front: "naar", back: "to" },
  { front: "van", back: "of" },
  { front: "een", back: "a" },
  { front: "ik", back: "I" },
  { front: "hebben", back: "to have" },
  { front: "dat", back: "that" },
  { front: "hij", back: "he" },
  { front: "niet", back: "not" },
  { front: "zijn", back: "his" },
  { front: "haar", back: "her" },
  { front: "het", back: "it" },
  { front: "u", back: "you" },
  { front: "met", back: "with" },
  { front: "voor", back: "for" },
  { front: "Te doen", back: "to do" },
  { front: "ze", back: "she" },
  { front: "zoals", back: "as" },
  { front: "op", back: "on" },
  { front: "zeggen", back: "to say" },
  { front: "op", back: "at" },
  { front: "hem", back: "him" },
  { front: "van", back: "from" },
  { front: "maar", back: "but" },
  { front: "mijn", back: "my" },
  { front: "gaan", back: "to go" },
  { front: "ze", back: "they" },
  { front: "allemaal", back: "all" },
  { front: "door", back: "by" },
  { front: "deze", back: "this" },
  { front: "een", back: "one" },
  { front: "uit", back: "out" },
  { front: "omhoog", back: "up" },
  { front: "weten", back: "to know" },
  { front: "zo", back: "so" },
  { front: "een", back: "an" },
  { front: "zien", back: "to see" },
  { front: "kon", back: "could" },
  { front: "of", back: "or" },
  { front: "hen", back: "them" },
  { front: "te krijgen", back: "to get" },
  { front: "wij", back: "we" },
  { front: "net zoals", back: "like" },
  { front: "komen", back: "to come" },
  { front: "wat", back: "what" },
  { front: "maken", back: "to make" },
  { front: "er", back: "there" },
  { front: "wat betreft", back: "about" },
  { front: "welke", back: "which" },
  { front: "hun", back: "their" },
  { front: "in", back: "into" },
  { front: "denken", back: "to think" },
  { front: "Kijken", back: "to look" },
  { front: "als", back: "if" },
  { front: "wie", back: "who" },
  { front: "wanneer", back: "when" },
  { front: "nemen", back: "to take" },
  { front: "tijd", back: "time" },
  { front: "Nee", back: "no" },
  { front: "terug", back: "back" },
  { front: "willen", back: "to will" },
  { front: "jouw", back: "your" },
  { front: "meer", back: "more" },
  { front: "dan", back: "then" },
  { front: "naar beneden", back: "down" },
  { front: "goed", back: "good" },
  { front: "over-", back: "over" },
  { front: "vertellen", back: "to tell" },
  { front: "nu", back: "now" },
  { front: "hand-", back: "hand" },
  { front: "sommige", back: "some" },
  { front: "willen", back: "to want" },
  { front: "net", back: "just" },
  { front: "enkel en alleen", back: "only" },
  { front: "dan", back: "than" },
  { front: "manier", back: "way" },
  { front: "geven", back: "to give" },
  { front: "anders", back: "other" },
  { front: "dag", back: "day" },
  { front: "oog", back: "eye" },
  { front: "voor", back: "before" },
  { front: "vragen", back: "to ask" },
  { front: "vinden", back: "to find" },
  { front: "twee", back: "two" },
  { front: "weinig", back: "little" },
  { front: "lang", back: "long" },
  { front: "heel", back: "very" },
  { front: "voelen", back: "to feel" },
  { front: "ieder", back: "any" },
  { front: "ding", back: "thing" },
  { front: "te", back: "too" },
  { front: "hier", back: "here" },
  { front: "nooit", back: "never" },
  { front: "Verlaten", back: "to leave" },
  { front: "persoon", back: "person" },
  { front: "oud", back: "old" },
  { front: "hoofd", back: "head" },
  { front: "draaien", back: "to turn" },
  { front: "nog een keer", back: "again" },
  { front: "door", back: "through" },
  { front: "zelfs", back: "even" },
  { front: "gezicht", back: "face" },
  { front: "veel", back: "much" },
  { front: "uit", back: "off" },
  { front: "ons", back: "us" },
  { front: "eerste", back: "first" },
  { front: "rechts", back: "right" },
  { front: "onze", back: "our" },
  { front: "hoe", back: "how" },
  { front: "waar", back: "where" },
  { front: "na", back: "after" },
  { front: "haar", back: "its" },
  { front: "vrouw", back: "woman" },
  { front: "weg", back: "away" },
  { front: "leven", back: "life" },
  { front: "lijken", back: "to seem" },
  { front: "bellen", back: "to call" },
  { front: "nog steeds", back: "still" },
  { front: "horen", back: "to hear" },
  { front: "jaar", back: "year" },
  { front: "eigen", back: "own" },
  { front: "werken", back: "to work" },
  { front: "moeten", back: "should" },
  { front: "plaats", back: "place" },
  { front: "kamer", back: "room" },
  { front: "goed", back: "well" },
  { front: "staan", back: "to stand" },
  { front: "moeten", back: "to must" },
  { front: "zichzelf", back: "himself" },
  { front: "in de omgeving van", back: "around" },
  { front: "deur-", back: "door" },
  { front: "naar macht", back: "to might" },
  { front: "iets", back: "something" },
  { front: "proberen", back: "to try" },
  { front: "houden van", back: "to love" },
  { front: "huis", back: "house" },
  { front: "nacht", back: "night" },
  { front: "zetten", back: "to put" },
  { front: "Super goed", back: "great" },
  { front: "zodanig", back: "such" },
  { front: "houden", back: "to keep" },
  { front: "zitten", back: "to sit" },
  { front: "laatste", back: "last" },
  { front: "beginnen", back: "to begin" },
  { front: "omdat", back: "because" },
  { front: "die", back: "those" },
  { front: "deze", back: "these" },
  { front: "woord", back: "word" },
  { front: "gebruiken", back: "to use" },
  { front: "nodig hebben", back: "to need" },
  { front: "openen", back: "to open" },
  { front: "vasthouden", back: "to hold" },
  { front: "een ander", back: "another" },
  { front: "terwijl", back: "while" },
  { front: "meest", back: "most" },
  { front: "praten", back: "to talk" },
  { front: "te laten", back: "to let" },
  { front: "op", back: "upon" },
  { front: "ver", back: "far" },
  { front: "zonder", back: "without" },
  { front: "huis", back: "home" },
  { front: "glimlachen", back: "to smile" },
  { front: "altijd", back: "always" },
  { front: "stem", back: "voice" },
  { front: "kind", back: "child" },
  { front: "vader", back: "father" },
  { front: "lopen", back: "to walk" },
  { front: "jong", back: "young" },
  { front: "om te betekenen", back: "to mean" },
  { front: "niets", back: "nothing" },
  { front: "rennen", back: "to run" },
  { front: "hoewel", back: "though" },
  { front: "tegen", back: "against" },
  { front: "moeder", back: "mother" },
  { front: "dezelfde", back: "same" },
  { front: "naam", back: "name" },
  { front: "spreken", back: "to speak" },
  { front: "veel", back: "many" },
  { front: "geest", back: "mind" },
  { front: "weinig", back: "few" },
  { front: "brengen", back: "to bring" },
  { front: "licht", back: "light" },
  { front: "sluiten", back: "to close" },
  { front: "kant", back: "side" },
  { front: "ooit", back: "ever" },
  { front: "bewegen", back: "to move" },
  { front: "mogen", back: "to may" },
  { front: "vriend", back: "friend" },
  { front: "elk", back: "every" },
  { front: "drie", back: "three" },
  { front: "een keer", back: "once" },
  { front: "genoeg", back: "enough" },
  { front: "worden", back: "to become" },
  { front: "meisje", back: "girl" },
  { front: "onder", back: "under" },
  { front: "nieuwe", back: "new" },
  { front: "einde", back: "end" },
  { front: "leven", back: "to live" },
  { front: "ook", back: "also" },
  { front: "helpen", back: "to help" },
  { front: "tussen", back: "between" },
  { front: "wereld-", back: "world" },
  { front: "vallen", back: "to fall" },
  { front: "beginnen", back: "to start" },
  { front: "elk", back: "each" },
  { front: "wachten", back: "to wait" },
  { front: "kijken", back: "to watch" },
  { front: "stoppen", back: "to stop" },
  { front: "iets", back: "anything" },
  { front: "beide", back: "both" },
  { front: "voet", back: "foot" },
  { front: "een deel", back: "part" },
  { front: "klein", back: "small" },
  { front: "tot", back: "until" },
  { front: "werkelijk", back: "really" },
  { front: "te beantwoorden", back: "to answer" },
  { front: "laten zien", back: "to show" },
  { front: "jongen", back: "boy" },
  { front: "zichzelf", back: "herself" },
  { front: "liegen", back: "to lie" },
  { front: "zeker", back: "sure" },
  { front: "Cursus", back: "course" },
  { front: "gebeuren", back: "to happen" },
  { front: "geloven", back: "to believe" },
  { front: "terugbrengen", back: "to return" },
  { front: "achter", back: "behind" },
  { front: "punt", back: "point" },
  { front: "volgende", back: "next" },
  { front: "nog", back: "yet" },
  { front: "hart-", back: "heart" },
  { front: "bijna", back: "almost" },
  { front: "instellen", back: "to set" },
  { front: "lichaam", back: "body" },
  { front: "waarom", back: "why" },
  { front: "slagen", back: "to pass" },
  { front: "ochtend-", back: "morning" },
  { front: "uur", back: "hour" },
  { front: "geluid", back: "sound" },
  { front: "ontmoeten", back: "to meet" },
  { front: "wit", back: "white" },
  { front: "onthouden", back: "to remember" },
  { front: "soort", back: "kind" },
  { front: "hopen", back: "to hope" },
  { front: "bereiken", back: "to reach" },
  { front: "sterven", back: "to die" },
  { front: "slecht", back: "bad" },
  { front: "voor de helft", back: "half" },
  { front: "lachen", back: "to laugh" },
  { front: "familie", back: "family" },
  { front: "sinds", back: "since" },
  { front: "hoog", back: "high" },
  { front: "boek", back: "book" },
  { front: "er toe doen", back: "matter" },
  { front: "stap", back: "step" },
  { front: "veranderen", back: "to change" },
  { front: "vraag", back: "question" },
  { front: "aan de overkant", back: "across" },
  { front: "begrijpen", back: "to understand" },
  { front: "volgen", back: "to follow" },
  { front: "samen", back: "together" },
  { front: "vrouw", back: "wife" },
  { front: "trekken", back: "to pull" },
  { front: "langs", back: "along" },
  { front: "tafel", back: "table" },
  { front: "spelen", back: "to play" },
  { front: "verliezen", back: "to lose" },
  { front: "groot", back: "big" },
  { front: "huilen", back: "to cry" },
  { front: "zwart", back: "black" },
  { front: "haar-", back: "hair" },
  { front: "lezen", back: "to read" },
  { front: "voorkant", back: "front" },
  { front: "versturen", back: "to send" },
  { front: "heel", back: "quite" },
  { front: "breken", back: "to break" },
  { front: "mezelf", back: "myself" },
  { front: "zullen", back: "to shall" },
  { front: "nu al", back: "already" },
  { front: "minuut", back: "minute" },
  { front: "donker", back: "dark" },
  { front: "spoedig", back: "soon" },
  { front: "in de richting van", back: "toward" },
  { front: "geheel", back: "whole" },
  { front: "auto", back: "car" },
  { front: "venster", back: "window" },
  { front: "schudden", back: "to shake" },
  { front: "anders", back: "else" },
  { front: "rust uit", back: "rest" },
  { front: "geld", back: "money" },
  { front: "feit", back: "fact" },
  { front: "zoon", back: "son" },
  { front: "schrijven", back: "to write" },
  { front: "brand", back: "fire" },
  { front: "tweede", back: "second" },
  { front: "te blijven", back: "to stay" },
  { front: "zich afvragen", back: "to wonder" },
  { front: "geval", back: "case" },
  { front: "verhaal", back: "story" },
  { front: "lijn", back: "line" },
  { front: "groeien", back: "to grow" },
  { front: "lucht", back: "air" },
  { front: "wensen", back: "to wish" },
  { front: "gedachte", back: "thought" },
  { front: "opstaan", back: "to rise" },
  { front: "minst", back: "least" },
  { front: "vol", back: "full" },
  { front: "vangen", back: "to catch" },
  { front: "leiden", back: "to lead" },
  { front: "groot", back: "large" },
  { front: "verschijnen", back: "to appear" },
  { front: "alles", back: "everything" },
  { front: "zorgen", back: "to care" },
  { front: "dragen", back: "to carry" },
  { front: "dood", back: "death" },
  { front: "slapen", back: "to sleep" },
  { front: "vermoorden", back: "to kill" },
  { front: "idee", back: "idea" },
  { front: "antwoorden", back: "to reply" },
  { front: "dragen", back: "to wear" },
  { front: "muur", back: "wall" },
  { front: "rijden", back: "to drive" },
  { front: "in de buurt", back: "near" },
  { front: "tekenen", back: "to draw" },
  { front: "schouder", back: "shoulder" },
  { front: "Verleden", back: "past" },
  { front: "dood", back: "dead" },
  { front: "vroeg", back: "early" },
  { front: "staren", back: "to stare" },
  { front: "alleen", back: "alone" },
  { front: "zin", back: "sense" },
  { front: "mond", back: "mouth" },
  { front: "liever", back: "rather" },
  { front: "dragen", back: "to bear" },
  { front: "vier", back: "four" },
  { front: "doorgaan", back: "to continue" },
  { front: "boom", back: "tree" },
  { front: "broer", back: "brother" },
  { front: "reden", back: "reason" },
  { front: "paard", back: "horse" },
  { front: "anderen", back: "others" },
  { front: "bestellen", back: "order" },
  { front: "vijf", back: "five" },
  { front: "aanraken", back: "to touch" },
  { front: "ronde", back: "round" },
  { front: "diep", back: "deep" },
  { front: "brief", back: "letter" },
  { front: "Missen", back: "Miss" },
  { front: "veronderstellen", back: "to suppose" },
  { front: "dwingen", back: "force" },
  { front: "stad-", back: "town" },
  { front: "eten", back: "to eat" },
  { front: "duidelijk", back: "clear" },
  { front: "trouwen", back: "to marry" },
  { front: "gooien", back: "to throw" },
  { front: "land", back: "country" },
  { front: "aanwezig", back: "present" },
  { front: "binnen", back: "inside" },
  { front: "verdieping", back: "floor" },
  { front: "betalen", back: "to pay" },
  { front: "knikken", back: "to nod" },
  { front: "vinger", back: "finger" },
  { front: "blijven", back: "to remain" },
  { front: "scheur", back: "tear" },
  { front: "straat", back: "street" },
  { front: "dame", back: "lady" },
  { front: "minder", back: "less" },
  { front: "angst", back: "fear" },
  { front: "iemand", back: "someone" },
  { front: "bedrijf", back: "business" },
  { front: "in staat", back: "able" },
  { front: "stoel", back: "chair" },
  { front: "vergeten", back: "to forget" },
  { front: "kiezen", back: "to pick" },
  { front: "verwachten", back: "to expect" },
  { front: "rood", back: "red" },
  { front: "macht", back: "power" },
  { front: "een blik te werpen", back: "to glance" },
  { front: "misschien", back: "perhaps" },
  { front: "kort", back: "short" },
  { front: "grond", back: "ground" },
  { front: "lip-", back: "lip" },
  { front: "echt", back: "real" },
  { front: "kleden", back: "to dress" },
  { front: "maand", back: "month" },
  { front: "luisteren", back: "to listen" },
  { front: "laat", back: "late" },
  { front: "school-", back: "school" },
  { front: "een van beide", back: "either" },
  { front: "wie", back: "whom" },
  { front: "laag", back: "low" },
  { front: "tussen", back: "among" },
  { front: "man", back: "husband" },
  { front: "toevoegen", back: "to add" },
  { front: "verschillend", back: "different" },
  { front: "laten vallen", back: "to drop" },
  { front: "drinken", back: "to drink" },
  { front: "leren", back: "to learn" },
  { front: "plotseling", back: "suddenly" },
  { front: "papier", back: "paper" },
  { front: "land-", back: "land" },
  { front: "soort", back: "sort" },
  { front: "vaak", back: "often" },
  { front: "avond", back: "evening" },
  { front: "bovenstaande", back: "above" },
  { front: "honderd", back: "hundred" },
  { front: "beslissen", back: "to decide" },
  { front: "opmerken", back: "to notice" },
  { front: "dochter", back: "daughter" },
  { front: "kantoor", back: "office" },
  { front: "koude", back: "cold" },
  { front: "figuur", back: "figure" },
  { front: "weg", back: "road" },
  { front: "gevoel", back: "feeling" },
  { front: "hangen", back: "to hang" },
  { front: "snijden", back: "to cut" },
  { front: "aantal", back: "number" },
  { front: "fijn", back: "fine" },
  { front: "stad", back: "city" },
  { front: "verrassen", back: "to surprise" },
  { front: "te verhogen", back: "to raise" },
  { front: "vullen", back: "to fill" },
  { front: "verscheidene", back: "several" },
  { front: "wiens", back: "whose" },
  { front: "arm", back: "poor" },
  { front: "zeker", back: "certain" },
  { front: "waarschijnlijk", back: "probably" },
  { front: "geleden", back: "ago" },
  { front: "veroorzaken", back: "to cause" },
  { front: "binnenkomen", back: "to enter" },
  { front: "klaar", back: "ready" },
  { front: "blauw", back: "blue" },
  { front: "binnen", back: "within" },
  { front: "zich", back: "themselves" },
  { front: "vooruit", back: "forward" },
  { front: "zus", back: "sister" },
  { front: "spenderen", back: "to spend" },
  { front: "staat", back: "state" },
  { front: "echter", back: "however" },
  { front: "vechten", back: "to fight" },
  { front: "sterk", back: "strong" },
  { front: "kussen", back: "to kiss" },
  { front: "gedurende", back: "during" },
  { front: "beetje", back: "bit" },
  { front: "plezieren", back: "to please" },
  { front: "buiten", back: "outside" },
  { front: "been", back: "leg" },
  { front: "Geachte", back: "dear" },
  { front: "gelukkig", back: "happy" },
  { front: "droom", back: "dream" },
  { front: "Notitie", back: "note" },
  { front: "fout", back: "wrong" },
  { front: "realiseren", back: "to realize" },
  { front: "interesseren", back: "interest" },
  { front: "bloed", back: "blood" },
  { front: "snel", back: "quickly" },
  { front: "uitleggen", back: "to explain" },
  { front: "menselijk", back: "human" },
  { front: "Heer", back: "Lord" },
  { front: "rijden", back: "to ride" },
  { front: "bedekken", back: "to cover" },
  { front: "leunen", back: "to lean" },
  { front: "toelaten", back: "to allow" },
  { front: "tien", back: "ten" },
  { front: "twijfel", back: "doubt" },
  { front: "twintig", back: "twenty" },
  { front: "mijnheer", back: "sir" },
  { front: "mooi", back: "beautiful" },
  { front: "oorlog", back: "war" },
  { front: "mooi", back: "pretty" },
  { front: "langzaam", back: "slowly" },
  { front: "mogelijk", back: "possible" },
  { front: "moeite", back: "trouble" },
  { front: "bezoeken", back: "to visit" },
  { front: "kans", back: "chance" },
  { front: "duwen", back: "to push" },
  { front: "gratis", back: "free" },
  { front: "adem", back: "breath" },
  { front: "stuk", back: "piece" },
  { front: "zon", back: "sun" },
  { front: "waarheid", back: "truth" },
  { front: "aankomen", back: "to arrive" },
  { front: "overwegen", back: "to consider" },
  { front: "of", back: "whether" },
  { front: "acteren", back: "to act" },
  { front: "zelf", back: "itself" },
  { front: "noch", back: "nor" },
  { front: "iedereen", back: "anyone" },
  { front: "teken", back: "sign" },
  { front: "transactie", back: "deal" },
  { front: "oversteken", back: "to cross" },
  { front: "glas", back: "glass" },
  { front: "baan", back: "job" },
  { front: "af te maken", back: "to finish" },
  { front: "fluisteren", back: "to whisper" },
  { front: "studeren", back: "to study" },
  { front: "het formulier", back: "form" },
  { front: "gemakkelijk", back: "easy" },
  { front: "leeftijd", back: "age" },
  { front: "afbeelding", back: "picture" },
  { front: "zes", back: "six" },
  { front: "Tenslotte", back: "finally" },
  { front: "kopen", back: "to buy" },
  { front: "stilte", back: "silence" },
  { front: "hond", back: "dog" },
  { front: "liggen", back: "to lay" },
  { front: "zicht", back: "sight" },
  { front: "oor", back: "ear" },
  { front: "aanbieden", back: "to offer" },
  { front: "schip", back: "ship" },
  { front: "jezelf", back: "yourself" },
  { front: "naar", back: "towards" },
  { front: "zee", back: "sea" },
  { front: "beloven", back: "to promise" },
  { front: "opheffen", back: "to lift" },
  { front: "vliegen", back: "to fly" },
  { front: "duizend", back: "thousand" },
  { front: "raden", back: "to guess" },
  { front: "hoek", back: "corner" },
  { front: "zich zorgen maken", back: "to worry" },
  { front: "uitzicht", back: "view" },
  { front: "probleem", back: "problem" },
  { front: "naast", back: "beside" },
  { front: "telefoon", back: "phone" },
  { front: "aandacht", back: "attention" },
  { front: "verstoppen", back: "to hide" },
  { front: "missen", back: "to miss" },
  { front: "staren", back: "gaze" },
  { front: "Politie", back: "police" },
  { front: "opslaan", back: "to save" },
  { front: "feest", back: "party" },
  { front: "Engels", back: "English" },
  { front: "steen", back: "stone" },
  { front: "Londen", back: "London" },
  { front: "vreemd", back: "strange" },
  { front: "bang", back: "afraid" },
  { front: "pijn", back: "pain" },
  { front: "Golf", back: "wave" },
  { front: "keuken-", back: "kitchen" },
  { front: "het eens zijn", back: "to agree" },
  { front: "staken", back: "to strike" },
  { front: "drukken", back: "to press" },
  { front: "groen", back: "green" },
  { front: "paar", back: "couple" },
  { front: "vent", back: "guy" },
  { front: "Sorry", back: "sorry" },
  { front: "ervaring", back: "experience" },
  { front: "tot", back: "till" },
  { front: "Amerikaans", back: "American" },
  { front: "kan zijn", back: "maybe" },
  { front: "stoel", back: "seat" },
  { front: "rollen", back: "to roll" },
  { front: "inderdaad", back: "indeed" },
  { front: "blazen", back: "to blow" },
  { front: "soms", back: "sometimes" },
  { front: "zwaar", back: "heavy" },
  { front: "ziel", back: "soul" },
  { front: "belangrijk", back: "important" },
  { front: "kind", back: "kid" },
  { front: "zorgen maken", back: "to concern" },
  { front: "de mijne", back: "mine" },
  { front: "positie", back: "position" },
  { front: "heet", back: "hot" },
  { front: "voorbij", back: "beyond" },
  { front: "schreeuwen", back: "to shout" },
  { front: "onderwerpen", back: "subject" },
  { front: "diner", back: "dinner" },
  { front: "controleren", back: "to check" },
  { front: "geest", back: "spirit" },
  { front: "middag", back: "afternoon" },
  { front: "officier", back: "officer" },
  { front: "stil", back: "quiet" },
  { front: "verlangen", back: "desire" },
  { front: "behalve", back: "except" },
  { front: "aarde", back: "earth" },
  { front: "inbeelden", back: "to imagine" },
  { front: "pauzeren", back: "to pause" },
  { front: "benaderen", back: "to approach" },
  { front: "nek", back: "neck" },
  { front: "mijl", back: "mile" },
  { front: "manier", back: "manner" },
  { front: "meedoen", back: "to join" },
  { front: "voedsel", back: "food" },
  { front: "gebouw", back: "building" },
  { front: "plakken", back: "to stick" },
  { front: "rand", back: "edge" },
  { front: "veld-", back: "field" },
  { front: "natuur", back: "nature" },
  { front: "rivier-", back: "river" },
  { front: "rots", back: "rock" },
  { front: "geweer", back: "gun" },
  { front: "vermelden", back: "to mention" },
  { front: "recht", back: "straight" },
  { front: "breed", back: "wide" },
  { front: "bedrijf", back: "company" },
  { front: "hemel", back: "sky" },
  { front: "schieten", back: "to shoot" },
  { front: "hout", back: "wood" },
  { front: "raken", back: "to hit" },
  { front: "dansen", back: "to dance" },
  { front: "menigte", back: "crowd" },
  { front: "verbranden", back: "to burn" },
  { front: "kameraad", back: "fellow" },
  { front: "uitdrukking", back: "expression" },
  { front: "doos", back: "box" },
  { front: "controle", back: "control" },
  { front: "kerk", back: "church" },
  { front: "zuchten", back: "to sigh" },
  { front: "iedereen", back: "everyone" },
  { front: "kiezen", back: "to choose" },
  { front: "delen", back: "to share" },
  { front: "aanbevelen", back: "to suggest" },
  { front: "koning", back: "king" },
  { front: "ouder", back: "parent" },
  { front: "leuk", back: "nice" },
  { front: "uitglijden", back: "to slip" },
  { front: "bouwen", back: "to build" },
  { front: "naar", back: "onto" },
  { front: "bijna", back: "nearly" },
  { front: "geheugen", back: "memory" },
  { front: "kleren", back: "clothes" },
  { front: "verslag doen van", back: "report" },
  { front: "eenvoudigweg", back: "simply" },
  { front: "accepteren", back: "to accept" },
  { front: "genieten", back: "to enjoy" },
  { front: "huid", back: "skin" },
  { front: "geheim", back: "secret" },
  { front: "zeker", back: "certainly" },
  { front: "spel", back: "game" },
  { front: "gesprek", back: "conversation" },
  { front: "boot", back: "boat" },
  { front: "leeg", back: "empty" },
  { front: "vandaag", back: "today" },
  { front: "hel", back: "hell" },
  { front: "serveren", back: "to serve" },
  { front: "zacht", back: "soft" },
  { front: "ontsnappen", back: "to escape" },
  { front: "toon", back: "tone" },
  { front: "haten", back: "to hate" },
  { front: "richting", back: "direction" },
  { front: "poging", back: "attempt" },
  { front: "hoewel", back: "although" },
  { front: "groep", back: "group" },
  { front: "wang", back: "cheek" },
  { front: "zak-", back: "pocket" },
  { front: "aankunnen", back: "to manage" },
  { front: "Ja", back: "yes" },
  { front: "zoeken", back: "to search" },
  { front: "ruiken", back: "to smell" },
  { front: "de lente", back: "spring" },
  { front: "algemeen", back: "general" },
  { front: "midden-", back: "middle" },
  { front: "links", back: "left" },
  { front: "precies", back: "exactly" },
  { front: "volgend op", back: "following" },
  { front: "pijn doen", back: "to hurt" },
  { front: "in rekening brengen", back: "charge" },
  { front: "openbaar", back: "public" },
  { front: "om te vestigen", back: "to settle" },
  { front: "genoegen", back: "pleasure" },
  { front: "in plaats daarvan", back: "instead" },
  { front: "ontdekken", back: "to discover" },
  { front: "heer", back: "gentleman" },
  { front: "goud", back: "gold" },
  { front: "wat dan ook", back: "whatever" },
  { front: "nieuws", back: "news" },
  { front: "knie", back: "knee" },
  { front: "helder", back: "bright" },
  { front: "per direct", back: "immediately" },
  { front: "blij", back: "glad" },
  { front: "verslaan", back: "to beat" },
  { front: "snel", back: "fast" },
  { front: "werkelijk", back: "actually" },
  { front: "afstand", back: "distance" },
  { front: "ontvangen", back: "to receive" },
  { front: "plek", back: "spot" },
  { front: "tafereel", back: "scene" },
  { front: "eisen", back: "to demand" },
  { front: "toegeven", back: "to admit" },
  { front: "trein", back: "train" },
  { front: "klasse", back: "class" },
  { front: "dier", back: "animal" },
  { front: "bureau", back: "desk" },
  { front: "hal", back: "hall" },
  { front: "borst", back: "chest" },
  { front: "meester", back: "master" },
  { front: "koffie", back: "coffee" },
  { front: "vertrouwen", back: "to trust" },
  { front: "bewaker", back: "guard" },
  { front: "stil", back: "silent" },
  { front: "schaduw", back: "shadow" },
  { front: "zingen", back: "to sing" },
  { front: "zak", back: "bag" },
  { front: "bewijzen", back: "to prove" },
  { front: "Frans", back: "French" },
  { front: "lang", back: "tall" },
  { front: "onder", back: "beneath" },
  { front: "zoeken", back: "to seek" },
  { front: "geen", back: "none" },
  { front: "haasten", back: "to rush" },
  { front: "berg-", back: "mountain" },
  { front: "voorbereiden", back: "to prepare" },
  { front: "soldaat", back: "soldier" },
  { front: "nauwelijks", back: "hardly" },
  { front: "grijnzen", back: "to grin" },
  { front: "geschiedenis", back: "history" },
  { front: "schoon", back: "clean" },
  { front: "verkopen", back: "to sell" },
  { front: "huwelijk", back: "marriage" },
  { front: "actie", back: "action" },
  { front: "dorp", back: "village" },
  { front: "lid", back: "member" },
  { front: "toekomst", back: "future" },
  { front: "heuvel", back: "hill" },
  { front: "vooral", back: "especially" },
  { front: "tuin-", back: "garden" },
  { front: "zoet", back: "sweet" },
  { front: "regen", back: "rain" },
  { front: "karakter", back: "character" },
  { front: "reizen", back: "to travel" },
  { front: "aanval", back: "attack" },
  { front: "sluiten", back: "to shut" },
  { front: "rook", back: "smoke" },
  { front: "veilig", back: "safe" },
  { front: "ruimte", back: "space" },
  { front: "Gebied", back: "area" },
  { front: "beneden", back: "below" },
  { front: "situatie", back: "situation" },
  { front: "te beoordelen", back: "to regard" },
  { front: "weigeren", back: "to refuse" },
  { front: "dertig", back: "thirty" },
  { front: "droog", back: "dry" },
  { front: "springen", back: "to jump" },
  { front: "herhalen", back: "to repeat" },
  { front: "op slot doen", back: "to lock" },
  { front: "Engeland", back: "England" },
  { front: "kunst", back: "art" },
  { front: "verder", back: "ahead" },
  { front: "derde", back: "third" },
  { front: "snel", back: "quick" },
  { front: "overhemd", back: "shirt" },
  { front: "winnen", back: "to win" },
  { front: "neus-", back: "nose" },
  { front: "zomer", back: "summer" },
  { front: "keel", back: "throat" },
  { front: "inspanning", back: "effort" },
  { front: "eenvoudig", back: "simple" },
  { front: "termijn", back: "term" },
  { front: "leren", back: "to teach" },
  { front: "langzaam", back: "slow" },
  { front: "plicht", back: "duty" },
  { front: "muziek-", back: "music" },
  { front: "Indiaas", back: "Indian" },
  { front: "evenement", back: "event" },
  { front: "bloem", back: "flower" },
  { front: "markeren", back: "to mark" },
  { front: "vogel", back: "bird" },
  { front: "verzamelen", back: "to gather" },
  { front: "Dhr", back: "Mr" },
  { front: "rechtbank", back: "court" },
  { front: "vergadering", back: "meeting" },
  { front: "schreeuwen", back: "to scream" },
  { front: "hoed", back: "hat" },
  { front: "falen", back: "to fail" },
  { front: "klimmen", back: "to climb" },
  { front: "moord", back: "murder" },
  { front: "passen", back: "to fit" },
  { front: "geen van beide", back: "neither" },
  { front: "dun", back: "thin" },
  { front: "resultaat", back: "result" },
  { front: "haasten", back: "to hurry" },
  { front: "compleet", back: "complete" },
  { front: "tand", back: "tooth" },
  { front: "vastbinden", back: "to tie" },
  { front: "doel", back: "purpose" },
  { front: "pagina", back: "page" },
  { front: "dus", back: "thus" },
  { front: "pak", back: "suit" },
  { front: "vijand", back: "enemy" },
  { front: "eeuw", back: "century" },
  { front: "moeite hebben met", back: "to struggle" },
  { front: "gebruikelijk", back: "usual" },
  { front: "voorwerp", back: "object" },
  { front: "wakker worden", back: "to wake" },
  { front: "rijk", back: "rich" },
  { front: "opeisen", back: "to claim" },
  { front: "eerlijk", back: "fair" },
  { front: "gemeenschappelijk", back: "common" },
  { front: "sterkte", back: "strength" },
  { front: "dik", back: "thick" },
  { front: "spul", back: "stuff" },
  { front: "eerbied", back: "respect" },
  { front: "adresseren", back: "to address" },
  { front: "leven", back: "living" },
  { front: "zeven", back: "seven" },
  { front: "herkennen", back: "to recognize" },
  { front: "te behoren", back: "to ought" },
  { front: "ondersteunen", back: "to support" },
  { front: "werf", back: "yard" },
  { front: "pakken", back: "to grab" },
  { front: "bruin", back: "brown" },
  { front: "commando", back: "command" },
  { front: "aanwezigheid", back: "presence" },
  { front: "omschrijven", back: "to describe" },
  { front: "jas", back: "coat" },
  { front: "noodzakelijk", back: "necessary" },
  { front: "zinken", back: "to sink" },
  { front: "uitrekken", back: "to stretch" },
  { front: "lijden", back: "to suffer" },
  { front: "plotseling", back: "sudden" },
  { front: "verdwijnen", back: "to disappear" },
  { front: "acht", back: "eight" },
  { front: "pad", back: "path" },
  { front: "bijzonder", back: "particular" },
  { front: "verspreiden", back: "to spread" },
  { front: "duisternis", back: "darkness" },
  { front: "trap", back: "stair" },
  { front: "bedanken", back: "to thank" },
  { front: "beweging", back: "movement" },
  { front: "moeilijk", back: "difficult" },
  { front: "winkel", back: "shop" },
  { front: "verbleken", back: "pale" },
  { front: "toebehoren", back: "to belong" },
  { front: "taal", back: "language" },
  { front: "speciaal", back: "special" },
  { front: "ernstig", back: "serious" },
  { front: "herinneren", back: "to remind" },
  { front: "voorzien", back: "to provide" },
  { front: "smal", back: "narrow" },
  { front: "staat", back: "condition" },
  { front: "buigen", back: "to bend" },
  { front: "ster", back: "star" },
  { front: "fles", back: "bottle" },
  { front: "levend", back: "alive" },
  { front: "sleutel", back: "key" },
  { front: "schommelen", back: "to swing" },
  { front: "luidruchtig", back: "loud" },
  { front: "zachtjes", back: "quietly" },
  { front: "vergissing", back: "mistake" },
  { front: "observeren", back: "to observe" },
  { front: "opmerken", back: "to remark" },
  { front: "schoonheid", back: "beauty" },
  { front: "voorzichtig", back: "carefully" },
  { front: "poort", back: "gate" },
  { front: "kloppen", back: "to knock" },
  { front: "glijden", back: "to slide" },
  { front: "bewust", back: "aware" },
  { front: "verwijderen", back: "to remove" },
  { front: "helemaal", back: "completely" },
  { front: "durven", back: "to dare" },
  { front: "knecht", back: "servant" },
  { front: "buigen", back: "to bow" },
  { front: "cirkel", back: "circle" },
  { front: "thee", back: "tea" },
  { front: "boos", back: "angry" },
  { front: "persoonlijk", back: "personal" },
  { front: "wolk", back: "cloud" },
  { front: "regel", back: "rule" },
  { front: "strijd", back: "battle" },
  { front: "boord", back: "board" },
  { front: "privaat", back: "private" },
  { front: "wond", back: "wound" },
  { front: "natuurlijk", back: "natural" },
  { front: "ergens", back: "somewhere" },
  { front: "voort", back: "forth" },
  { front: "smaak", back: "taste" },
  { front: "repareren", back: "to fix" },
  { front: "gemakkelijk", back: "easily" },
  { front: "hoe dan ook", back: "anyway" },
  { front: "schepsel", back: "creature" },
  { front: "lengte", back: "length" },
  { front: "op te slaan", back: "store" },
  { front: "vers", back: "fresh" },
  { front: "wijn", back: "wine" },
  { front: "appartement", back: "apartment" },
  { front: "gelegenheid", back: "occasion" },
  { front: "beeld", back: "image" },
  { front: "systeem", back: "system" },
  { front: "rechter", back: "judge" },
  { front: "tong", back: "tongue" },
  { front: "pond", back: "pound" },
  { front: "kop", back: "cup" },
  { front: "maken", back: "to create" },
  { front: "vorm", back: "shape" },
  { front: "waard", back: "worth" },
  { front: "lied", back: "song" },
  { front: "produceren", back: "to produce" },
  { front: "vanavond", back: "tonight" },
  { front: "ziek", back: "ill" },
  { front: "sneeuw", back: "snow" },
  { front: "niveau", back: "level" },
  { front: "dwaas", back: "fool" },
  { front: "daarom", back: "therefore" },
  { front: "tellen", back: "to count" },
  { front: "ziek", back: "sick" },
  { front: "sociaal", back: "social" },
  { front: "morgen", back: "tomorrow" },
  { front: "detail-", back: "detail" },
  { front: "mening", back: "opinion" },
  { front: "shouders ophalen", back: "to shrug" },
  { front: "betrekken", back: "to involve" },
  { front: "reusachtig", back: "huge" },
  { front: "gieten", back: "to pour" },
  { front: "stoer", back: "cool" },
  { front: "borst", back: "breast" },
  { front: "vermoeien", back: "to tire" },
  { front: "licht", back: "slightly" },
  { front: "kamp", back: "camp" },
  { front: "voorbeeld", back: "example" },
  { front: "reis", back: "trip" },
  { front: "paar-", back: "pair" },
  { front: "verhaal", back: "tale" },
  { front: "flitsen", back: "to flash" },
  { front: "waarschijnlijk", back: "likely" },
  { front: "doorgaans", back: "usually" },
  { front: "onmogelijk", back: "impossible" },
  { front: "vreselijk", back: "terrible" },
  { front: "maatschappij", back: "society" },
  { front: "stelen", back: "to steal" },
  { front: "vrede", back: "peace" },
  { front: "bericht", back: "message" },
  { front: "slaapkamer", back: "bedroom" },
  { front: "affaire", back: "affair" },
  { front: "optreden", back: "to occur" },
  { front: "nodig hebben", back: "to require" },
  { front: "schoen", back: "shoe" },
  { front: "van plan zijn", back: "to intend" },
  { front: "warmte", back: "heat" },
  { front: "kleur", back: "color" },
  { front: "leger", back: "army" },
  { front: "vreemdeling", back: "stranger" },
  { front: "druk", back: "busy" },
  { front: "grijs", back: "gray" },
  { front: "Duitse", back: "German" },
  { front: "bevatten", back: "to contain" },
  { front: "geel", back: "yellow" },
  { front: "kaart", back: "card" },
  { front: "scherp", back: "sharp" },
  { front: "behandelen", back: "to treat" },
  { front: "kalmte", back: "calm" },
  { front: "bal", back: "ball" },
  { front: "bodem", back: "bottom" },
  { front: "Gevaar", back: "danger" },
  { front: "geheel", back: "entire" },
  { front: "om vast te stellen", back: "to determine" },
  { front: "slechts", back: "merely" },
  { front: "vis", back: "fish" },
  { front: "hoofd", back: "main" },
  { front: "verven", back: "to paint" },
  { front: "casten", back: "to cast" },
  { front: "schrijver", back: "author" },
  { front: "lawaai", back: "noise" },
  { front: "boosheid", back: "anger" },
  { front: "verschil", back: "difference" },
  { front: "gast", back: "guest" },
  { front: "verdenken", back: "to suspect" },
  { front: "schok", back: "shock" },
  { front: "schot", back: "shot" },
  { front: "chef", back: "chief" },
  { front: "schijnen", back: "to shine" },
  { front: "Wassen", back: "to wash" },
  { front: "ademen", back: "to breathe" },
  { front: "regering", back: "government" },
  { front: "vermijden", back: "to avoid" },
  { front: "stadium", back: "stage" },
  { front: "vijftig", back: "fifty" },
  { front: "gat", back: "hole" },
  { front: "auteur", back: "writer" },
  { front: "uitbarsten", back: "to burst" },
  { front: "keuze", back: "choice" },
  { front: "zilver", back: "silver" },
  { front: "uitroepen", back: "to exclaim" },
  { front: "klein", back: "tiny" },
  { front: "gras", back: "grass" },
  { front: "leiden", back: "to direct" },
  { front: "verschijning", back: "appearance" },
  { front: "Amerika", back: "America" },
  { front: "prachtig", back: "wonderful" },
  { front: "inpakken", back: "to pack" },
  { front: "ziekenhuis", back: "hospital" },
  { front: "de hare", back: "hers" },
  { front: "voorzichtig", back: "gently" },
  { front: "zacht", back: "softly" },
  { front: "spoor", back: "track" },
  { front: "bewijsmateriaal", back: "evidence" },
  { front: "slecht", back: "evil" },
  { front: "onthullen", back: "to reveal" },
  { front: "bestaan", back: "to exist" },
  { front: "slepen", back: "to drag" },
  { front: "bidden", back: "to pray" },
  { front: "kennis", back: "knowledge" },
  { front: "uitdrukken", back: "to express" },
  { front: "terzijde", back: "aside" },
  { front: "vertrouwd", back: "familiar" },
  { front: "periode", back: "period" },
  { front: "blok", back: "block" },
  { front: "duidelijk", back: "clearly" },
  { front: "morren", back: "to murmur" },
  { front: "stroom", back: "stream" },
  { front: "vegen", back: "to sweep" },
  { front: "omstandigheid", back: "circumstance" },
  { front: "aandringen", back: "to insist" },
  { front: "kwartaal", back: "quarter" },
  { front: "hersenen", back: "brain" },
  { front: "vlakte", back: "plain" },
  { front: "vlak", back: "flat" },
  { front: "kwestie", back: "issue" },
  { front: "baseren", back: "base" },
  { front: "genot", back: "delight" },
  { front: "eiland", back: "island" },
  { front: "Parijs", back: "Paris" },
  { front: "kans", back: "opportunity" },
  { front: "fabriek", back: "plant" },
  { front: "vreugde", back: "joy" },
  { front: "verschuiven", back: "to shift" },
  { front: "verhouding", back: "relationship" },
  { front: "mes", back: "knife" },
  { front: "poetsen", back: "to brush" },
  { front: "gering", back: "slight" },
  { front: "vloek", back: "damn" },
  { front: "beven", back: "to tremble" },
  { front: "te bespreken", back: "to discuss" },
  { front: "divers", back: "various" },
  { front: "waarde", back: "value" },
  { front: "seks", back: "sex" },
  { front: "lokaal", back: "local" },
  { front: "jeugd", back: "youth" },
  { front: "praktijk", back: "practice" },
  { front: "nat", back: "wet" },
  { front: "ontbijt", back: "breakfast" },
  { front: "gezagvoerder", back: "captain" },
  { front: "vernietigen", back: "to destroy" },
  { front: "reis", back: "journey" },
  { front: "zondag", back: "Sunday" },
  { front: "hoe dan ook", back: "somehow" },
  { front: "fronsen", back: "to frown" },
  { front: "inpakken", back: "to wrap" },
  { front: "kat", back: "cat" },
  { front: "gebonden", back: "bound" },
  { front: "gebaar", back: "gesture" },
  { front: "priester", back: "priest" },
  { front: "Frankrijk", back: "France" },
  { front: "ermee omgaan", back: "to handle" },
  { front: "hemel", back: "heaven" },
  { front: "getuige", back: "witness" },
  { front: "verhogen", back: "to increase" },
  { front: "voorzien zijn van", back: "feature" },
  { front: "om te schoppen", back: "to kick" },
  { front: "aannemen", back: "to assume" },
  { front: "in slaap", back: "asleep" },
  { front: "herinneren", back: "to recall" },
  { front: "wedstrijd", back: "match" },
  { front: "strak", back: "tight" },
  { front: "Bos", back: "forest" },
  { front: "beschermen", back: "to protect" },
  { front: "gebrek", back: "lack" },
  { front: "metgezel", back: "companion" },
  { front: "geheel", back: "entirely" },
  { front: "besluit", back: "decision" },
  { front: "opnemen", back: "to include" },
  { front: "spoor", back: "trail" },
  { front: "uitnodigen", back: "to invite" },
  { front: "emotie", back: "emotion" },
  { front: "bot", back: "bone" },
  { front: "uur", back: "o’clock" },
  { front: "omgeven", back: "to surround" },
  { front: "laatste", back: "final" },
  { front: "oppervlakte", back: "surface" },
  { front: "dozijn", back: "dozen" },
  { front: "verklaren", back: "to declare" },
  { front: "wapen", back: "weapon" },
  { front: "centrum", back: "center" },
  { front: "Welkom", back: "welcome" },
  { front: "misdrijf", back: "crime" },
  { front: "gewicht", back: "weight" },
  { front: "minnaar", back: "lover" },
  { front: "zwaard", back: "sword" },
  { front: "lijst", back: "list" },
  { front: "datum", back: "date" },
  { front: "bijwonen", back: "to attend" },
  { front: "toespraak", back: "speech" },
  { front: "Christelijk", back: "Christian" },
  { front: "verzekeren", back: "to assure" },
  { front: "snappen", back: "to snap" },
  { front: "beweging", back: "motion" },
  { front: "passie", back: "passion" },
  { front: "om verder te gaan", back: "to advance" },
  { front: "invloed", back: "influence" },
  { front: "tenzij", back: "unless" },
  { front: "snelheid", back: "speed" },
  { front: "mensen", back: "folk" },
  { front: "maan", back: "moon" },
  { front: "voeden", back: "to feed" },
  { front: "politiek", back: "political" },
  { front: "smeken", back: "to beg" },
  { front: "overeenstemmen", back: "to accord" },
  { front: "veertig", back: "forty" },
  { front: "negen", back: "nine" },
  { front: "loslaten", back: "to release" },
  { front: "noorden", back: "north" },
  { front: "oom", back: "uncle" },
  { front: "oude", back: "ancient" },
  { front: "verdrietig", back: "sad" },
  { front: "Brits", back: "British" },
  { front: "flauw", back: "faint" },
  { front: "dubbele", back: "double" },
  { front: "graf", back: "grave" },
  { front: "ogenblik", back: "instant" },
  { front: "bord", back: "plate" },
  { front: "begraven", back: "to bury" },
  { front: "volmaakt", back: "perfectly" },
  { front: "heerlijk", back: "lovely" },
  { front: "de jouwe", back: "yours" },
  { front: "ijs-", back: "ice" },
  { front: "scheiden", back: "to separate" },
  { front: "bijten", back: "to bite" },
  { front: "dak", back: "roof" },
  { front: "zweren", back: "to swear" },
  { front: "duim", back: "inch" },
  { front: "bestuurder", back: "driver" },
  { front: "spiegel", back: "mirror" },
  { front: "maag", back: "stomach" },
  { front: "wezen", back: "being" },
  { front: "verkrijgen", back: "to gain" },
  { front: "negeren", back: "to ignore" },
  { front: "oke", back: "okay" },
  { front: "reageren", back: "to respond" },
  { front: "niemand", back: "nobody" },
  { front: "tegenover", back: "opposite" },
  { front: "lastig vallen", back: "to bother" },
  { front: "regelen", back: "to arrange" },
  { front: "bagageruimte", back: "boot" },
  { front: "stof", back: "dust" },
  { front: "wrijven", back: "to rub" },
  { front: "direct", back: "directly" },
  { front: "gloed", back: "glow" },
  { front: "schreeuwen", back: "to yell" },
  { front: "individu", back: "individual" },
  { front: "verpleegster", back: "nurse" },
  { front: "Mvr", back: "Mrs" },
  { front: "visie", back: "vision" },
  { front: "verspillen", back: "to waste" },
  { front: "trots", back: "proud" },
  { front: "boos", back: "mad" },
  { front: "autoriteit", back: "authority" },
  { front: "krant-", back: "newspaper" },
  { front: "Kerstmis-", back: "Christmas" },
  { front: "risico", back: "risk" },
  { front: "vooral", back: "particularly" },
  { front: "mate", back: "degree" },
  { front: "voormalig", back: "former" },
  { front: "iets", back: "somewhat" },
  { front: "stijl", back: "style" },
  { front: "iemand", back: "somebody" },
  { front: "bezitten", back: "to possess" },
  { front: "vrachtauto", back: "truck" },
  { front: "interessant", back: "interesting" },
  { front: "grap", back: "joke" },
  { front: "te mompelen", back: "to mutter" },
  { front: "eigendom", back: "property" },
  { front: "kaal", back: "bare" },
  { front: "vlees", back: "flesh" },
  { front: "reliëf", back: "relief" },
  { front: "twijfelen", back: "to hesitate" },
  { front: "verlichten", back: "to ease" },
  { front: "greep", back: "grip" },
  { front: "springen", back: "to leap" },
  { front: "levering", back: "supply" },
  { front: "onderbreken", back: "to interrupt" },
  { front: "maaltijd", back: "meal" },
  { front: "neef", back: "cousin" },
  { front: "werkwijze", back: "process" },
  { front: "vrouw", back: "female" },
  { front: "verlies", back: "loss" },
  { front: "sigaret", back: "cigarette" },
  { front: "ijzer", back: "iron" },
  { front: "overtuigen", back: "to convince" },
  { front: "deel", back: "apart" },
  { front: "zin in hebben", back: "fancy" },
  { front: "rij", back: "row" },
  { front: "tempo", back: "pace" },
  { front: "tweemaal", back: "twice" },
  { front: "vloeien", back: "to flow" },
  { front: "geduldig", back: "patient" },
  { front: "doen alsof", back: "to pretend" },
  { front: "grootte", back: "size" },
  { front: "nauwelijks", back: "barely" },
  { front: "huwelijk", back: "wedding" },
  { front: "aankondigen", back: "to announce" },
  { front: "gelach", back: "laughter" },
  { front: "vel", back: "sheet" },
  { front: "ontwerp", back: "design" },
  { front: "koken", back: "to cook" },
  { front: "uw", back: "thy" },
  { front: "wiel", back: "wheel" },
  { front: "succes", back: "success" },
  { front: "gevaarlijk", back: "dangerous" },
  { front: "zuiden", back: "south" },
  { front: "wakker", back: "awake" },
  { front: "los", back: "loose" },
  { front: "voorhoofd", back: "forehead" },
  { front: "breed", back: "broad" },
  { front: "woestijn", back: "desert" },
  { front: "roeren", back: "to stir" },
  { front: "beroerte", back: "stroke" },
  { front: "vleugel", back: "wing" },
  { front: "waarschuwen", back: "to warn" },
  { front: "vouwen", back: "to fold" },
  { front: "stapel", back: "pile" },
  { front: "vlam", back: "flame" },
  { front: "Ingang", back: "entrance" },
  { front: "heer", back: "lord" },
  { front: "zeilen", back: "to sail" },
  { front: "introduceren", back: "to introduce" },
  { front: "glad", back: "smooth" },
  { front: "krachtig", back: "powerful" },
  { front: "kosten", back: "cost" },
  { front: "miljoen", back: "million" },
  { front: "geloof", back: "faith" },
  { front: "slikken", back: "to swallow" },
  { front: "brug", back: "bridge" },
  { front: "maatregel", back: "measure" },
  { front: "Blind", back: "blind" },
  { front: "iedereen", back: "everybody" },
  { front: "fortuin", back: "fortune" },
  { front: "ten gevolge", back: "due" },
  { front: "teder", back: "gentle" },
  { front: "onderzoeken", back: "to examine" },
  { front: "gek", back: "crazy" },
  { front: "pret", back: "fun" },
  { front: "trots", back: "pride" },
  { front: "mannetje", back: "male" },
  { front: "deelnemen", back: "to engage" },
  { front: "montuur", back: "frame" },
  { front: "realiteit", back: "reality" },
  { front: "gepast", back: "proper" },
  { front: "reflecteren", back: "to reflect" },
  { front: "te dwalen", back: "to wander" },
  { front: "te representeren", back: "to represent" },
  { front: "weer", back: "weather" },
  { front: "bevredigen", back: "to satisfy" },
  { front: "moeilijkheid", back: "difficulty" },
  { front: "zwak", back: "weak" },
  { front: "betekenis", back: "meaning" },
  { front: "vlucht", back: "flight" },
  { front: "aangenaam", back: "pleasant" },
  { front: "dek", back: "deck" },
  { front: "voorzichtig", back: "careful" },
  { front: "plein", back: "square" },
  { front: "excuus", back: "excuse" },
  { front: "firma", back: "firm" },
  { front: "tak", back: "branch" },
  { front: "vegen", back: "to wipe" },
  { front: "prijs", back: "price" },
  { front: "origineel", back: "original" },
  { front: "twaalf", back: "twelve" },
  { front: "advocaat", back: "lawyer" },
  { front: "spoor", back: "trace" },
  { front: "gebed", back: "prayer" },
  { front: "iemand", back: "anybody" },
  { front: "eer", back: "honor" },
  { front: "klok", back: "bell" },
  { front: "Christus", back: "Christ" },
  { front: "energie", back: "energy" },
  { front: "mogelijk", back: "possibly" },
  { front: "gewoonte", back: "habit" },
  { front: "gewillig", back: "willing" },
  { front: "kwaliteit", back: "quality" },
  { front: "gooien", back: "to toss" },
  { front: "fout", back: "fault" },
  { front: "verlagen", back: "to lower" },
  { front: "zeker", back: "surely" },
  { front: "blijkbaar", back: "apparently" },
  { front: "ruzie maken", back: "to argue" },
  { front: "begin", back: "beginning" },
  { front: "knap", back: "handsome" },
  { front: "diep", back: "deeply" },
  { front: "beschuldigen", back: "to blame" },
  { front: "protesteren", back: "to protest" },
  { front: "gevangene", back: "prisoner" },
  { front: "aangeven", back: "to indicate" },
  { front: "u", back: "thee" },
  { front: "draaien", back: "to twist" },
  { front: "jas", back: "jacket" },
  { front: "held", back: "hero" },
  { front: "geluk", back: "luck" },
  { front: "inhoud", back: "content" },
  { front: "informeren", back: "to inform" },
  { front: "voorkomen", back: "to prevent" },
  { front: "geluk", back: "happiness" },
  { front: "werkelijk", back: "truly" },
  { front: "ontwikkelen", back: "to develop" },
  { front: "kin", back: "chin" },
  { front: "te gronde richten", back: "to ruin" },
  { front: "breken", back: "to crack" },
  { front: "leider", back: "leader" },
  { front: "gisteren", back: "yesterday" },
  { front: "vijftien", back: "fifteen" },
  { front: "houten", back: "wooden" },
  { front: "afleveren", back: "to deliver" },
  { front: "middel", back: "agent" },
  { front: "materiaal", back: "material" },
  { front: "antwoord", back: "response" },
  { front: "dom", back: "stupid" },
  { front: "mode", back: "fashion" },
  { front: "taak", back: "task" },
  { front: "nieuwsgierig", back: "curious" },
  { front: "slagen", back: "to succeed" },
  { front: "wijs", back: "wise" },
  { front: "bedrag", back: "amount" },
  { front: "telefoon", back: "telephone" },
  { front: "ontkennen", back: "to deny" },
  { front: "graven", back: "to dig" },
  { front: "wet", back: "law" },
  { front: "aandringen", back: "to urge" },
  { front: "voor altijd", back: "forever" },
  { front: "gemeenschap", back: "community" },
  { front: "fysiek", back: "physical" },
  { front: "bron", back: "source" },
  { front: "leraar", back: "teacher" },
  { front: "slaaf", back: "slave" },
  { front: "dik", back: "fat" },
  { front: "voorkeur hebben voor", back: "to prefer" },
  { front: "leger", back: "military" },
  { front: "brood", back: "bread" },
  { front: "verwijzen", back: "to refer" },
  { front: "cabine", back: "cabin" },
  { front: "geheel", back: "fully" },
  { front: "niet in staat", back: "unable" },
  { front: "vergezellen", back: "to accompany" },
  { front: "verder gaan", back: "to proceed" },
  { front: "uitwisselen", back: "to exchange" },
  { front: "massa-", back: "mass" },
  { front: "verzoek", back: "request" },
  { front: "bewerkstelligen", back: "to establish" },
  { front: "vreemd", back: "odd" },
  { front: "kust-", back: "shore" },
  { front: "gidsen", back: "to guide" },
  { front: "gouden", back: "golden" },
  { front: "onszelf", back: "ourselves" },
  { front: "louter", back: "mere" },
  { front: "relatie", back: "relation" },
  { front: "bedreigen", back: "to threaten" },
  { front: "tarief", back: "rate" },
  { front: "vervloeken", back: "to curse" },
  { front: "bier", back: "beer" },
  { front: "afgelegen", back: "distant" },
  { front: "voor de hand liggend", back: "obvious" },
  { front: "commentaar", back: "comment" },
  { front: "edele", back: "noble" },
  { front: "voordeel", back: "advantage" },
  { front: "wrok", back: "spite" },
  { front: "het dossier", back: "file" },
  { front: "mogelijkheid", back: "possibility" },
  { front: "uitvoeren", back: "to conduct" },
  { front: "vervagen", back: "to fade" },
  { front: "concentreren", back: "to focus" },
  { front: "scherm", back: "screen" },
  { front: "bestaan", back: "existence" },
  { front: "opsteigen", back: "to mount" },
  { front: "zand", back: "sand" },
  { front: "slachtoffer", back: "victim" },
  { front: "woede", back: "rage" },
  { front: "teller", back: "counter" },
  { front: "laatstgenoemde", back: "latter" },
  { front: "bang maken", back: "to scare" },
  { front: "ongeval", back: "accident" },
  { front: "indruk", back: "impression" },
  { front: "te vergelijken", back: "to peer" },
  { front: "homoseksueel", back: "gay" },
  { front: "krullen", back: "to curl" },
  { front: "verzamelen", back: "to collect" },
  { front: "marcheren", back: "to march" },
  { front: "weergeven", back: "to display" },
  { front: "strand", back: "beach" },
  { front: "tante", back: "aunt" },
  { front: "deuropening", back: "doorway" },
  { front: "comfortabel", back: "comfortable" },
  { front: "afdrijven", back: "to drift" },
  { front: "jammer", back: "pity" },
  { front: "opwinding", back: "excitement" },
  { front: "arresteren", back: "to arrest" },
  { front: "duidelijk", back: "obviously" },
  { front: "anders-", back: "otherwise" },
  { front: "handel", back: "trade" },
  { front: "cel", back: "cell" },
  { front: "Gezondheid", back: "health" },
  { front: "westen", back: "west" },
  { front: "leer", back: "leather" },
  { front: "ruw", back: "rough" },
  { front: "hijgen", back: "to gasp" },
  { front: "presteren", back: "to perform" },
  { front: "roze", back: "pink" },
  { front: "zin", back: "sentence" },
  { front: "humeur", back: "mood" },
  { front: "artikel", back: "article" },
  { front: "keten", back: "chain" },
  { front: "vervoer", back: "carriage" },
  { front: "stamelen", back: "to utter" },
  { front: "schaduw", back: "shade" },
  { front: "vlak", back: "plane" },
  { front: "vergeven", back: "to forgive" },
  { front: "gedicht", back: "poem" },
  { front: "touw", back: "rope" },
  { front: "aanleg", back: "instance" },
  { front: "zuiver", back: "pure" },
  { front: "Laden", back: "to load" },
  { front: "grijpen", back: "to seize" },
  { front: "achterkant", back: "rear" },
  { front: "eerlijk", back: "honest" },
  { front: "groot", back: "major" },
  { front: "soortgelijk", back: "similar" },
  { front: "activiteit", back: "activity" },
  { front: "echoën", back: "to echo" },
  { front: "bezetten", back: "to occupy" },
  { front: "beroemd", back: "famous" },
  { front: "overleven", back: "to survive" },
  { front: "angstig", back: "anxious" },
  { front: "grappig", back: "funny" },
  { front: "duivel", back: "devil" },
  { front: "vertrouwen", back: "confidence" },
  { front: "betreuren", back: "to regret" },
  { front: "begaan", back: "to commit" },
  { front: "zweet", back: "sweat" },
  { front: "Russisch", back: "Russian" },
  { front: "reeks", back: "range" },
  { front: "herstellen", back: "to recover" },
  { front: "verschrikking", back: "horror" },
  { front: "veiligheid", back: "security" },
  { front: "bemanning", back: "crew" },
  { front: "grommen", back: "to roar" },
  { front: "dageraad", back: "dawn" },
  { front: "natie", back: "nation" },
  { front: "metaal", back: "metal" },
  { front: "nerveus", back: "nervous" },
  { front: "gevangenis", back: "prison" },
  { front: "Verlaten", back: "to abandon" },
  { front: "overal", back: "anywhere" },
  { front: "dichter", back: "poet" },
  { front: "zijn", back: "sin" },
  { front: "naar gras", back: "to grasp" },
  { front: "houding", back: "attitude" },
  { front: "beveiligen", back: "to secure" },
  { front: "verklaring", back: "statement" },
  { front: "naakt", back: "naked" },
  { front: "rekening", back: "bill" },
  { front: "voorhoofd", back: "brow" },
  { front: "moraliteit", back: "moral" },
  { front: "rolle", back: "role" },
  { front: "overvloed", back: "plenty" },
  { front: "carrière", back: "career" },
  { front: "staart", back: "tail" },
  { front: "geboorte", back: "birth" },
  { front: "toepassen", back: "to apply" },
  { front: "officieel", back: "official" },
  { front: "om te vertellen", back: "to relate" },
  { front: "lot", back: "fate" },
  { front: "vallei", back: "valley" },
  { front: "verbeelding", back: "imagination" },
  { front: "bang maken", back: "to frighten" },
  { front: "markt", back: "market" },
  { front: "vuist", back: "fist" },
  { front: "naar ovens", back: "to owe" },
  { front: "intentie", back: "intention" },
  { front: "verbinding", back: "connection" },
  { front: "serie", back: "series" },
  { front: "moed", back: "courage" },
  { front: "toren", back: "tower" },
  { front: "meer", back: "lake" },
  { front: "te voorschijn komen", back: "to emerge" },
  { front: "inzetten", back: "to bet" },
  { front: "film", back: "movie" },
  { front: "rok", back: "skirt" },
  { front: "huilen", back: "to weep" },
  { front: "kamer", back: "chamber" },
  { front: "proces", back: "trial" },
  { front: "magie", back: "magic" },
  { front: "motor", back: "engine" },
  { front: "dank", back: "thanks" },
  { front: "schrift", back: "writing" },
  { front: "knop", back: "button" },
  { front: "jagen", back: "to hunt" },
  { front: "gewoon", back: "ordinary" },
  { front: "uitbreiden", back: "to extend" },
  { front: "om te redden", back: "to spare" },
  { front: "theorie", back: "theory" },
  { front: "normaal", back: "normal" },
  { front: "vast", back: "steady" },
  { front: "verlenen", back: "to grant" },
  { front: "juni", back: "June" },
  { front: "Jood", back: "Jew" },
  { front: "tekst", back: "text" },
  { front: "absoluut", back: "absolutely" },
  { front: "eer", back: "honour" },
  { front: "drijven", back: "to float" },
  { front: "mysterie", back: "mystery" },
  { front: "seizoen", back: "season" },
  { front: "eigenaar", back: "owner" },
  { front: "zich veroorloven", back: "to afford" },
  { front: "kleur", back: "colour" },
  { front: "advies", back: "advice" },
  { front: "bewonderen", back: "to admire" },
  { front: "pet", back: "cap" },
  { front: "vrijheid", back: "freedom" },
  { front: "twee blikken", back: "to glare" },
  { front: "verdienen", back: "to deserve" },
  { front: "groeten", back: "to greet" },
  { front: "knuffelen", back: "to hug" },
  { front: "personeel", back: "staff" },
  { front: "stoten", back: "to thrust" },
  { front: "naderhand", back: "afterwards" },
  { front: "afhankelijk zijn", back: "to depend" },
  { front: "zwemmen", back: "to swim" },
  { front: "zwembad", back: "pool" },
  { front: "signaal", back: "signal" },
  { front: "onschuldig", back: "innocent" },
  { front: "hiel", back: "heel" },
  { front: "generelt", back: "generally" },
  { front: "gordijn", back: "curtain" },
  { front: "bezit", back: "possession" },
  { front: "foto", back: "photograph" },
  { front: "nauwelijks", back: "scarcely" },
  { front: "inheems", back: "native" },
  { front: "grijs", back: "grey" },
  { front: "formulier", back: "blanket" },
  { front: "toestaan", back: "to permit" },
  { front: "vies", back: "dirty" },
  { front: "schande", back: "shame" },
  { front: "ophouden", back: "to cease" },
  { front: "ei", back: "egg" },
  { front: "toelichting", back: "explanation" },
  { front: "toehoorders", back: "audience" },
  { front: "afschuwelijk", back: "awful" },
  { front: "pijp", back: "pipe" },
  { front: "te spannen", back: "to strain" },
  { front: "kunstenaar", back: "artist" },
  { front: "persen", back: "to squeeze" },
  { front: "roman", back: "Roman" },
  { front: "in beroep gaan", back: "to appeal" },
  { front: "doek", back: "cloth" },
  { front: "terreur", back: "terror" },
  { front: "oosten", back: "east" },
  { front: "sectie", back: "section" },
  { front: "storen", back: "to disturb" },
  { front: "rang", back: "rank" },
  { front: "vriendschappelijk", back: "friendly" },
  { front: "hongerig", back: "hungry" },
  { front: "kruipen", back: "to creep" },
  { front: "bezoeker", back: "visitor" },
  { front: "overal", back: "everywhere" },
  { front: "religieus", back: "religious" },
  { front: "verkrijgen", back: "to obtain" },
  { front: "vlees", back: "meat" },
  { front: "meid", back: "maid" },
  { front: "gerechtigheid", back: "justice" },
  { front: "vooruitgang", back: "progress" },
  { front: "schoot", back: "lap" },
  { front: "boven", back: "upstairs" },
  { front: "geloof", back: "belief" },
  { front: "verbinden", back: "to connect" },
  { front: "roman", back: "novel" },
  { front: "spook", back: "ghost" },
  { front: "streven", back: "to aim" },
  { front: "gooien", back: "to fling" },
  { front: "zaterdag", back: "Saturday" },
  { front: "chirurgie", back: "operation" },
  { front: "verlichten", back: "to relieve" },
  { front: "meer", back: "anymore" },
  { front: "draaft", back: "despite" },
  { front: "taille", back: "waist" },
  { front: "melk", back: "milk" },
  { front: "omarmen", back: "to embrace" },
  { front: "badkamer", back: "bathroom" },
  { front: "ontmoeten", back: "to encounter" },
  { front: "landgoed", back: "estate" },
  { front: "voorgaand", back: "previous" },
  { front: "draaien", back: "to spin" },
  { front: "fictie", back: "fiction" },
  { front: "groots", back: "grand" },
  { front: "val", back: "trap" },
  { front: "beïnvloeden", back: "to affect" },
  { front: "truc", back: "trick" },
  { front: "zijde", back: "silk" },
  { front: "soepen", back: "supper" },
  { front: "dronken", back: "drunk" },
  { front: "wenk", back: "hint" },
  { front: "vervangen", back: "to replace" },
  { front: "verontwaardigd", back: "harm" },
  { front: "elleboog", back: "elbow" },
  { front: "om af te dalen", back: "to descend" },
  { front: "twee verliezen", back: "to tap" },
  { front: "veranda", back: "porch" },
  { front: "opzwellen", back: "to swell" },
  { front: "ups", back: "upper" },
  { front: "politieagent", back: "cop" },
  { front: "grootvader", back: "grandfather" },
  { front: "oefening", back: "exercise" },
  { front: "bibliotheek", back: "library" },
  { front: "spier", back: "muscle" },
  { front: "bevriezen", back: "to freeze" },
  { front: "overstuur", back: "to upset" },
  { front: "klagen", back: "to complain" },
  { front: "Europa", back: "Europe" },
  { front: "gunst", back: "favor" },
  { front: "wortel", back: "root" },
  { front: "beest", back: "beast" },
  { front: "opstaan", back: "to arise" },
  { front: "uitdaging", back: "challenge" },
  { front: "douche", back: "shower" },
  { front: "Grieks", back: "Greek" },
  { front: "overal", back: "throughout" },
  { front: "seksueel", back: "sexual" },
  { front: "snaar", back: "string" },
  { front: "limiet", back: "limit" },
  { front: "religie", back: "religion" },
  { front: "druk", back: "pressure" },
  { front: "verdwijnen", back: "to vanish" },
  { front: "gratie", back: "grace" },
  { front: "groot", back: "vast" },
  { front: "bekennen", back: "to confess" },
  { front: "offer", back: "sacrifice" },
  { front: "aankomst", back: "arrival" },
  { front: "rukken", back: "to jerk" },
  { front: "les", back: "lesson" },
  { front: "heup", back: "hip" },
  { front: "vertrekken", back: "lad" },
  { front: "olie", back: "oil" },
  { front: "patroon", back: "pattern" },
  { front: "regelmatig", back: "regular" },
  { front: "geweer", back: "rifle" },
  { front: "gelukkig", back: "lucky" },
  { front: "ezel", back: "ass" },
  { front: "dof", back: "dull" },
  { front: "bewust", back: "conscious" },
  { front: "knoeien", back: "mess" },
  { front: "kreunen", back: "to groan" },
  { front: "konsekvens", back: "consequence" },
  { front: "balans", back: "balance" },
  { front: "beginsel", back: "principle" },
  { front: "genegenheid", back: "affection" },
  { front: "stroom", back: "current" },
  { front: "kaars", back: "candle" },
  { front: "stront", back: "shit" },
  { front: "vlooien", back: "to flee" },
  { front: "hoogte", back: "height" },
  { front: "voorraad", back: "stock" },
  { front: "ridder", back: "knight" },
  { front: "klok", back: "clock" },
  { front: "kasteel", back: "castle" },
  { front: "hek", back: "fence" },
  { front: "schuldig", back: "guilty" },
  { front: "op te lossen", back: "to resolve" },
  { front: "knielen", back: "to kneel" },
  { front: "om te ontspannen", back: "to relax" },
  { front: "tempel", back: "temple" },
  { front: "behalve", back: "besides" },
  { front: "tijdschrift", back: "magazine" },
  { front: "favoriet", back: "favorite" },
  { front: "gezeten", back: "seated" },
  { front: "april", back: "April" },
  { front: "traditie", back: "tradition" },
  { front: "waarderen", back: "to appreciate" },
  { front: "wetenschap", back: "science" },
  { front: "populair", back: "popular" },
  { front: "grootmoeder", back: "grandmother" },
  { front: "twee rillen", back: "to shiver" },
  { front: "dagelijks", back: "daily" },
  { front: "bespreking", back: "discussion" },
  { front: "prins", back: "prince" },
  { front: "betoveren", back: "charm" },
  { front: "strippen", back: "to strip" },
  { front: "om te besluiten", back: "to conclude" },
  { front: "beschrijving", back: "description" },
  { front: "plafond", back: "ceiling" },
  { front: "struik", back: "bush" },
  { front: "VALSE", back: "FALSE" },
  { front: "intersted", back: "interested" },
  { front: "van nabij", back: "closely" },
  { front: "vastklampen", back: "to cling" },
  { front: "bank", back: "bench" },
  { front: "najagen", back: "to pursue" },
  { front: "dapper", back: "brave" },
  { front: "tevredenheid", back: "satisfaction" },
  { front: "kruipen", back: "to crawl" },
  { front: "literair", back: "literary" },
  { front: "bloedig", back: "bloody" },
  { front: "vergelijken", back: "to compare" },
  { front: "buitenlands", back: "foreign" },
  { front: "voorstellen", back: "to propose" },
  { front: "om te informeren", back: "to inquire" },
  { front: "verdriet", back: "grief" },
  { front: "hulp", back: "aid" },
  { front: "vriendschap", back: "friendship" },
  { front: "om te crashen", back: "to crash" },
  { front: "avontuur", back: "adventure" },
  { front: "vechten", back: "to stride" },
  { front: "cultuur", back: "culture" },
  { front: "balk", back: "beam" },
  { front: "veiligheid", back: "safety" },
  { front: "mars", back: "March" },
  { front: "bril", back: "glasses" },
  { front: "evne", back: "ability" },
  { front: "stevig", back: "firmly" },
  { front: "begrip", back: "understanding" },
  { front: "staal", back: "steel" },
  { front: "zenuw", back: "nerve" },
  { front: "engel", back: "angel" },
  { front: "reus", back: "giant" },
  { front: "achterdocht", back: "suspicion" },
  { front: "onbekend", back: "unknown" },
  { front: "schrikken", back: "to startle" },
  { front: "gelijk", back: "equal" },
  { front: "lachen", back: "to gleam" },
  { front: "generatie", back: "generation" },
  { front: "verzetten", back: "to resist" },
  { front: "snikken", back: "to sob" },
  { front: "När ooit", back: "whenever" },
  { front: "spellen", back: "spell" },
  { front: "reactie", back: "reaction" },
  { front: "onderwijs", back: "education" },
  { front: "bewijs", back: "proof" },
  { front: "opwinden", back: "to excite" },
  { front: "schijnen", back: "to blink" },
  { front: "zweep", back: "to whip" },
  { front: "identificeren", back: "to identify" },
  { front: "kom", back: "bowl" },
  { front: "blootstellen", back: "to expose" },
  { front: "waarschuwing", back: "warning" },
  { front: "diepte", back: "depth" },
  { front: "hoofdstuk", back: "chapter" },
  { front: "pijn doen", back: "to ache" },
  { front: "nippen", back: "to sip" },
  { front: "hard", back: "heavily" },
  { front: "Italiaans", back: "Italian" },
  { front: "wenkbrauw", back: "eyebrow" },
  { front: "grinniken", back: "to chuckle" },
  { front: "paleis", back: "palace" },
  { front: "ernstig", back: "seriously" },
  { front: "zich terugtrekken", back: "to retreat" },
  { front: "schilderij", back: "painting" },
  { front: "viktigheten", back: "importance" },
  { front: "koningin", back: "queen" },
  { front: "zwijgend", back: "silently" },
  { front: "pols", back: "wrist" },
  { front: "naar slib", back: "to slam" },
  { front: "verantwoordelijkheid", back: "responsibility" },
  { front: "helemaal", back: "altogether" },
  { front: "kaak", back: "jaw" },
  { front: "slecht", back: "badly" },
  { front: "passagier", back: "passenger" },
  { front: "juli", back: "July" },
  { front: "bekwaamheid", back: "skill" },
  { front: "missie", back: "mission" },
  { front: "achtervolgen", back: "to chase" },
  { front: "gewoonte", back: "custom" },
  { front: "te verzorgen", back: "to tend" },
  { front: "werkwijze", back: "method" },
  { front: "koe", back: "cow" },
  { front: "gretig", back: "eager" },
  { front: "krijger", back: "warrior" },
  { front: "koppelen", back: "to clutch" },
  { front: "waarnemen", back: "to perceive" },
  { front: "grot", back: "cave" },
  { front: "lof", back: "praise" },
  { front: "in staat", back: "capable" },
  { front: "huren", back: "to hire" },
  { front: "versie", back: "version" },
  { front: "buur", back: "neighbor" },
  { front: "verbergen", back: "to conceal" },
  { front: "boren", back: "to bore" },
  { front: "sympathie", back: "sympathy" },
  { front: "draad", back: "wire" },
  { front: "nieuwsgierigheid", back: "curiosity" },
  { front: "twee verplicht", back: "to oblige" },
  { front: "riem", back: "belt" },
  { front: "relatief", back: "relative" },
  { front: "notie", back: "notion" },
  { front: "vastleggen", back: "to capture" },
  { front: "om te schakelen", back: "to switch" },
  { front: "divan", back: "couch" },
  { front: "gang", back: "corridor" },
  { front: "vertrekken", back: "to depart" },
  { front: "ogenblikkelijk", back: "instantly" },
  { front: "Spaans", back: "Spanish" },
  { front: "bedreiging", back: "threat" },
  { front: "zeer", back: "highly" },
  { front: "tenslotte", back: "eventually" },
  { front: "gebruiken", back: "to employ" },
  { front: "afwezigheid", back: "absence" },
  { front: "wanhoop", back: "despair" },
  { front: "structuur", back: "structure" },
  { front: "eenzaam", back: "lonely" },
  { front: "dankbaar", back: "grateful" },
  { front: "zich terugtrekken", back: "to withdraw" },
  { front: "kaart", back: "map" },
  { front: "meestal", back: "mostly" },
  { front: "kussen", back: "pillow" },
  { front: "zichtbaar", back: "visible" },
  { front: "vaartuig", back: "vessel" },
  { front: "minnares", back: "mistress" },
  { front: "bevestigen", back: "to attach" },
  { front: "delicaat", back: "delicate" },
  { front: "verwarren", back: "to confuse" },
  { front: "professioneel", back: "professional" },
  { front: "warmte", back: "warmth" },
  { front: "gebroken", back: "broken" },
  { front: "uitputten", back: "to exhaust" },
  { front: "dom", back: "silly" },
  { front: "droefheid", back: "sorrow" },
  { front: "zadel", back: "saddle" },
  { front: "schade", back: "damage" },
  { front: "mooi", back: "rare" },
  { front: "verraden", back: "to betray" },
  { front: "slapen", back: "to slap" },
  { front: "erkennen", back: "to acknowledge" },
  { front: "toga", back: "gown" },
  { front: "solide", back: "solid" },
  { front: "uiterst", back: "extremely" },
  { front: "uitdrukking", back: "phrase" },
  { front: "spijker", back: "nail" },
  { front: "schoonmaken", back: "to rent" },
  { front: "onderhouden", back: "to maintain" },
  { front: "augustus", back: "August" },
  { front: "indruk maken", back: "to impress" },
  { front: "arbeider", back: "worker" },
  { front: "kogel", back: "bullet" },
  { front: "romp", back: "trunk" },
  { front: "konkluderer", back: "conclusion" },
  { front: "geweer", back: "pistol" },
  { front: "huisje", back: "cottage" },
  { front: "briljant", back: "brilliant" },
  { front: "burger", back: "citizen" },
  { front: "snel", back: "rapidly" },
  { front: "fluiten", back: "to whistle" },
  { front: "onlangs", back: "recently" },
  { front: "wanhopig", back: "desperate" },
  { front: "lichtjes", back: "lightly" },
  { front: "verwarring", back: "confusion" },
  { front: "lelijk", back: "ugly" },
  { front: "verstand", back: "intelligence" },
  { front: "bed", back: "sofa" },
  { front: "schuren", back: "to shed" },
  { front: "lieveling", back: "darling" },
  { front: "pa", back: "dad" },
  { front: "bries", back: "breeze" },
  { front: "lika", back: "equally" },
  { front: "band", back: "tape" },
  { front: "te wagen", back: "to venture" },
  { front: "krabben", back: "to scratch" },
  { front: "geur", back: "scent" },
  { front: "aantrekken", back: "to attract" },
  { front: "ontwikkeling", back: "development" },
  { front: "twee lammen", back: "to halt" },
  { front: "vastspelden", back: "to pin" },
  { front: "duwen", back: "to shove" },
  { front: "medisch", back: "medical" },
  { front: "helling", back: "slope" },
  { front: "natuurlijk", back: "naturally" },
  { front: "geestelijk", back: "mental" },
  { front: "verdedigen", back: "to defend" },
  { front: "verdienen", back: "to earn" },
  { front: "bidden", back: "to bid" },
  { front: "vuil", back: "dirt" },
  { front: "schelp", back: "shell" },
  { front: "kroon", back: "crown" },
  { front: "geslaagd", back: "successful" },
  { front: "deugd", back: "virtue" },
  { front: "overstroming", back: "flood" },
  { front: "portemonnee", back: "purse" },
  { front: "poëzie", back: "poetry" },
  { front: "poppen", back: "to pop" },
  { front: "buik", back: "belly" },
  { front: "totaal", back: "total" },
  { front: "bevestigen", back: "to confirm" },
  { front: "oordeel", back: "judgment" },
  { front: "Enorme", back: "enormous" },
  { front: "verpletteren", back: "to crush" },
  { front: "basketbal", back: "basket" },
  { front: "schuilplaats", back: "shelter" },
  { front: "kloppen", back: "to pat" },
  { front: "ansvarlig", back: "responsible" },
  { front: "bewustzijn", back: "consciousness" },
  { front: "Senaste", back: "recent" },
  { front: "delen", back: "to divide" },
  { front: "crimineel", back: "criminal" },
  { front: "kostbaar", back: "precious" },
  { front: "tamelijk", back: "fairly" },
  { front: "aanmoedigen", back: "to encourage" },
  { front: "grens", back: "border" },
  { front: "oceaan", back: "ocean" },
  { front: "bladeren", back: "blade" },
  { front: "dij", back: "thigh" },
  { front: "begrafenis", back: "funeral" },
  { front: "afdeling", back: "department" },
  { front: "ongebruikelijk", back: "unusual" },
  { front: "twee overtuigingen", back: "to persuade" },
  { front: "voertuig", back: "vehicle" },
  { front: "vrezen", back: "dread" },
  { front: "achtergrond", back: "background" },
  { front: "standaard", back: "standard" },
  { front: "televisie", back: "television" },
  { front: "beschuldigen", back: "to accuse" },
  { front: "helemaal", back: "totally" },
  { front: "voordeel", back: "benefit" },
  { front: "associëren", back: "to associate" },
  { front: "twee renderen", back: "to render" },
  { front: "klerk", back: "clerk" },
  { front: "toestemming", back: "permission" },
  { front: "wettelijk", back: "legal" },
  { front: "kust", back: "coast" },
  { front: "machtig", back: "mighty" },
  { front: "angst", back: "anxiety" },
  { front: "titel", back: "title" },
  { front: "onderzoek", back: "research" },
  { front: "redden", back: "to rescue" },
  { front: "boer", back: "farmer" },
  { front: "geweld", back: "violence" },
  { front: "glimp", back: "glimpse" },
  { front: "suggestie", back: "suggestion" },
  { front: "kinderjaren", back: "childhood" },
  { front: "twee zuchten", back: "to suck" },
  { front: "dwaas", back: "foolish" },
  { front: "beloning", back: "reward" },
  { front: "haak", back: "hook" },
  { front: "verduisteren", back: "dim" },
  { front: "klant", back: "client" },
  { front: "waardig", back: "worthy" },
  { front: "mysterieus", back: "mysterious" },
  { front: "strak", back: "tightly" },
  { front: "wreed", back: "cruel" },
  { front: "scherp", back: "sharply" },
  { front: "kip", back: "chicken" },
  { front: "gewaad", back: "robe" },
  { front: "sensatie", back: "sensation" },
  { front: "struikelen", back: "to stumble" },
  { front: "instructie", back: "instruction" },
  { front: "som", back: "sum" },
  { front: "twee huiverden", back: "to shudder" },
  { front: "meubilair", back: "furniture" },
  { front: "vertraging", back: "delay" },
  { front: "prestatie", back: "performance" },
  { front: "opleiding", back: "training" },
  { front: "mouw", back: "sleeve" },
  { front: "schat", back: "treasure" },
  { front: "duim", back: "thumb" },
  { front: "om te springen", back: "to dash" },
  { front: "zestig", back: "sixty" },
  { front: "modder", back: "mud" },
  { front: "te verslaan", back: "to defeat" },
  { front: "lade", back: "drawer" },
  { front: "verhalend", back: "narrative" },
  { front: "oranje", back: "orange" },
  { front: "knap", back: "clever" },
  { front: "blozen", back: "to blush" },
  { front: "plaats", back: "site" },
  { front: "functie", back: "function" },
  { front: "hardop", back: "aloud" },
  { front: "kennismaking", back: "acquaintance" },
  { front: "kapitaal", back: "capital" },
  { front: "rijkdom", back: "wealth" },
  { front: "identiteit", back: "identity" },
  { front: "glorie", back: "glory" },
  { front: "pik", back: "cock" },
  { front: "troepen", back: "troops" },
  { front: "baard", back: "beard" },
  { front: "constante", back: "constant" },
  { front: "mislukking", back: "failure" },
  { front: "gastheer", back: "host" },
  { front: "verkeer", back: "traffic" },
  { front: "vrijdag", back: "Friday" },
  { front: "blaffen", back: "to bark" },
  { front: "vergeefs", back: "vain" },
  { front: "spugen", back: "to spit" },
  { front: "kilte", back: "chill" },
  { front: "leerling", back: "eleven" },
  { front: "beneden", back: "downstairs" },
  { front: "arbeid", back: "labor" },
  { front: "vermoeid", back: "weary" },
  { front: "hervatten", back: "to resume" },
  { front: "ceremonie", back: "ceremony" },
  { front: "middernacht", back: "midnight" },
  { front: "moe", back: "tired" },
  { front: "vierde", back: "fourth" },
  { front: "pijnlijk", back: "painful" },
  { front: "hoek", back: "angle" },
  { front: "revamp", back: "useful" },
  { front: "reputatie", back: "reputation" },
  { front: "baas", back: "boss" },
  { front: "huishouden", back: "household" },
  { front: "nabijgelegen", back: "nearby" },
  { front: "afwachten", back: "to await" },
  { front: "onmiddellijk", back: "immediate" },
  { front: "hevig", back: "violent" },
  { front: "buitengewoon", back: "extraordinary" },
  { front: "broek", back: "pants" },
  { front: "fonds", back: "fond" },
  { front: "beschaamd", back: "ashamed" },
  { front: "gehoorzamen", back: "to obey" },
  { front: "werkelijk", back: "actual" },
];

export const getRandomPairs = (size = 50) =>
  wordPairs
    .slice()
    .sort(() => (Math.random() > Math.random() ? 1 : -1))
    .slice(0, size);
